<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fun on Varun Pant</title><link>https://varunpant.com/tags/fun/</link><description>Recent content in fun on Varun Pant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunpant.com/tags/fun/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>how to print bar chart in chrome browser console</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-print-bar-chart-in-chrome-browser-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-print-bar-chart-in-chrome-browser-console/</guid><description>This post doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything valuable to contribute, just some cool console trick.
Have you ever wanted to plot out a chart, very quickly ? Did you ever had an urge to visualise a bunch of numbers without having to use a charting api or copy pasting the data in a spreadsheet ? If you did then you might even learn something today :)
Here is a simple , yet neat way to plot out bunch of numbers in chrome console as a** horizontal bar chart.</description></item><item><title>Raphael-js-tutorial-part-II</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/raphael-js-tutorial-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/raphael-js-tutorial-part-ii/</guid><description>This is second part of the tutorial about getting started with Raphael.js. To see this first part go here.
Writing Text with Raphael Some code first ;)
var canvas = Raphael(0, 0, 250, 250 ); var t1 = canvas.text(50, 50, *&amp;#34;Some text Goes here&amp;#34;*); var t2 = canvas.text(60,90,&amp;#34;First line \n Second Line \n Third line&amp;#34;); var t3 = canvas.text(214, 140, &amp;#34;1079&amp;#34;).attr({&amp;#34;text-anchor&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;middle&amp;#34;,&amp;#39;font-size&amp;#39;:16,&amp;#34;font-family&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;arial&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;fill&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;#fff&amp;#34;}); In the above examples canvas.text will create a simple text element at 50,50.</description></item><item><title>LIMBO Game Review</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/limbo-game-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/limbo-game-review/</guid><description>LIMBO is a horrifically beautiful, monochrome or rather a gray-scale purgatory painted perhaps while watching Tim burton movie on the side. It was published initially in Jul 2010 by Microsoft Game Studios(XBLA) and Playdead(PSN, Windows), and then later released for Windows platform by Steam.
The primary character of the game is a boy, who wakes up right at the beginning of the game i.e while you are trying to figure out WTF is happening or wonder if you graphics driver (windows platform) screwed up or something, but there as you are fiddling with the movement buttons in keyboard you will see pair of bright white eyes flickering, and that’s when you start falling in love with the game and the care of detail added in a game which is totally unlike other in its league.</description></item><item><title>Liquid Particles</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/liquid-particles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/liquid-particles/</guid><description>After ages of constantly being one of the most used browser as well as a serious pain in Butt!!! IE is finally about to mature into something good and perhaps a useful software , with its support to most of the standards being used today , IE will join back the league of web 3.0 browsers, hopefully very soon
So I was going through various experiments done with Canvas and came across a great example on Liquid Particle physics simulation, which amazingly is written in JavaScript and Canvas element, I was so mesmerized by the application that I had to port it to SilverLight, using WritableBitmap.</description></item><item><title>Image Carousel</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/image-carousel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/image-carousel/</guid><description>Here is another of many JavaScript based Image Carousel, I had seen many similar to these made in SilverLight and Flash, I came across a wonderful carousel made in SilverLight sometimes back which was very fluid in behavior and could easily be customized and configured to take various shape and form.
I have managed to port it to JavaScript, it works best on chrome or FF, hope this would be fun to play with.</description></item><item><title>I-Phone Scroll</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/i-phone-scroll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/i-phone-scroll/</guid><description>One of the amazing features of i-phone user interface is smooth panning/scrolling animation.
I-phone “List Scrolling” perhaps gives a very funky and usable List –View to its users and allows them to scroll up and down the interface without any need of a scroll bar.
This interface is sensitive to the push speed and also shows traces of resilience.
I have been experimenting with various techniques to bring out similar effect using JavaScript and HTML, I am not quite sure if this would be useful in its present form but with some modifications may be this sample could prove its worthiness somewhere.</description></item><item><title>Notepad++ with Python</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/notepad-with-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/notepad-with-python/</guid><description>After reading an excellent article by Kazi Manzur Rashidon setting up a development environment for Iron Ruby using Notepad++, I was immediately struck with an idea of using the same excellent tool with Python 2.6.
Now don’t get me wrong here, theoretically there is nothing wrong with IDLE, but having a light weight IDE for those who don’t want to use Pydevplugin for Aptanaor Eclipse, I think Notepad++ is indeed a nice little dev tool.</description></item></channel></rss>