<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Varun Pant</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Varun Pant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>how to install the latest python 3 on mac</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-the-latest-python-3-on-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-the-latest-python-3-on-mac/</guid><description>Here is a quick guide on installing Python3 on a mac
Installation brew update brew upgrade sudo mkdir -p /usr/local/Frameworks sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/* brew install python3 brew link python3 brew doctor I hope this is useful</description></item><item><title>how to play apple music on alexa in uk</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-play-apple-music-on-alexa-in-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-play-apple-music-on-alexa-in-uk/</guid><description>You can now use Alexa to play Apple Music on Amazon Echo speakers.
It's just available for Echo devices and now customers in UK can also connect their apple music account with Alexa.
Open the Alexa app then sign into your Amazon account and make sure that your Echo device is connected.
Open Menu (top left icon), then select settings.
Select Music.
Select &amp;ldquo;Link New Service&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>download file using webdriver firefox and python selenium</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/download-file-using-webdriver-firefox-and-python-selenium/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/download-file-using-webdriver-firefox-and-python-selenium/</guid><description>Selenium is one of my favourite tool for automation.
In this post, I will demonstrate some basic code to download a file from a website in a headless mode , and also provide a docker file to make things simpler.
Python Code Here is some basic code which will make an attempt to download a **7zip exe. **
from pyvirtualdisplay import Display from selenium import webdriver from selenium.webdriver.support.ui import WebDriverWait from selenium.</description></item><item><title>web crawling or scraping using scrapy in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/web-crawling-or-scraping-using-scrapy-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/web-crawling-or-scraping-using-scrapy-in-python/</guid><description>Scrapy is a very popular web scraping/crawling framework, I have been using it for quite some time now.
In this post, I will demonstrate creating a very basic web crawler.
Install Scrapy Installation is via pip pip install scrapy
Minimalistic Code A very simple scraper is created like this
import scrapy class MySpider(scrapy.Spider): name = &amp;ldquo;MySpider&amp;rdquo; start_urls = [&amp;lsquo;https://varunpant.com'] def parse(self, response): # Get page title using xpath. page_title = response.</description></item><item><title>integration testing with apache beam using pubsub and bigtable emulators and direct runner</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/integration-testing-with-apache-beam-using-pubsub-and-bigtable-emulators-and-direct-runner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/integration-testing-with-apache-beam-using-pubsub-and-bigtable-emulators-and-direct-runner/</guid><description>Summary Recently I have been looking into ways to test my Apache Beam pipelines at work. Most common use cases of Beam generally involves either batch reading data from GCS and writing to analytical platforms such as Big Query or stream reading data from Pubsub and writing to perhaps Bigtable.
A pipelines consists of transforms and its generally easy to test them in isolation as a independent unit test per stage, however I am personally a big fan of &amp;ldquo;end-to-end&amp;rdquo; testing or “Integration testing” and this is where things can sometimes get tricky.</description></item><item><title>gdal 2 on mac with homebrew</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/gdal-2-on-mac-with-homebrew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/gdal-2-on-mac-with-homebrew/</guid><description>GDAL is one of the most frequently used utility in my toolkit. I am writing this post to make it easier for others to install it from scratch on their macs.
Setting up GDAL The traditional way has always been to visit the dear old kyngchaos.com, and install “GDAL Complete” Framework vi deb installer. Do make sure that GDAL Framework is in your path otherwise something like this always helps</description></item><item><title>how to print bar chart in chrome browser console</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-print-bar-chart-in-chrome-browser-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-print-bar-chart-in-chrome-browser-console/</guid><description>This post doesn't really have anything valuable to contribute, just some cool console trick.
Have you ever wanted to plot out a chart, very quickly ? Did you ever had an urge to visualise a bunch of numbers without having to use a charting api or copy pasting the data in a spreadsheet ? If you did then you might even learn something today :)
Here is a simple , yet neat way to plot out bunch of numbers in chrome console as a** horizontal bar chart.</description></item><item><title>how to make https requests with python httplib2 ssl</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-make-https-requests-with-python-httplib2-ssl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-make-https-requests-with-python-httplib2-ssl/</guid><description>Here are few snippets to make secure http requests using various python libraries.
httplib2 import httplib2 link = &amp;ldquo;https://example.com h = httplib2.Http(&amp;quot;.cache&amp;rdquo;) r, content = h.request(link, &amp;ldquo;GET&amp;rdquo;) ##### another exmaple
import httplib2 h = httplib2.Http(&amp;quot;.cache&amp;rdquo;) h.add_credentials(&amp;lsquo;user&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;pass&amp;rsquo;) r, content = h.request(&amp;ldquo;https://api.github.com&amp;quot;, &amp;ldquo;GET&amp;rdquo;) print r[&amp;lsquo;status&amp;rsquo;] print r[&amp;lsquo;content-type&amp;rsquo;] ### Urllib2
Here is a simmilar example using urlib2 for comparison and lines of code.
import urllib2 gh_url = &amp;lsquo;https://example.com' auth_handler = urllib2.HTTPBasicAuthHandler() auth_handler.add_password(None, gh_url, &amp;lsquo;user&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;password&amp;rsquo;) opener = urllib2.</description></item><item><title>how to read json from web http request of url via python urllib</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-read-json-from-web-http-request-of-url-via-python-urllib/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-read-json-from-web-http-request-of-url-via-python-urllib/</guid><description>I generally am looking for a quick snippet to issue an http request using urllib2 lib.
Here is a quick snippet to do so
url = &amp;ldquo;https://api.waqi.info/mapq/bounds/?bounds=%20-180.0,-85.0,180.0,85.0&amp;quot; import urllib2 import json from pprint import pprint req = urllib2.Request(url) opener = urllib2.build_opener() f = opener.open(req) #data varibale recieves the parsed json data = json.loads(f.read()) print len(data) for r in data: pprint(r) print &amp;ldquo;-&amp;quot;*50 Hope this helps</description></item><item><title>minimum insertions to form a palindrome</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/minimum-insertions-to-form-a-palindrome/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/minimum-insertions-to-form-a-palindrome/</guid><description>Brute-force approach Here I present a few approaches to deduce &amp;ldquo;minimum insertions&amp;rdquo; required to convert a string into a palindrome.
The basic brute force approach is quite simple, given a string with length L, start comparing, the first character from left and the last character while scanning inwards.
Here is a basic test for a palindrome.
def ispalindrome(s): L = len(s) for i in range(L): if s[i] != s[L - i - 1]: return False,i,L-i -1 return True,0,0 The above code returns True if the string is a palindrome or returns False with mismatching indices.</description></item><item><title>Inverse weighted distance interpolation in golang</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/inverse-weighted-distance-interpolation-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/inverse-weighted-distance-interpolation-in-golang/</guid><description>Inverse distance weighting (IDW) is a type of deterministic method for multivariate interpolation with a known scattered set of points. The assigned values to unknown points are calculated with a weighted average of the values available at the known points.
This technique, explicitly makes the assumption that things that are close to one another are more alike than those that are farther apart. To predict a value for any unmeasured location, IDW uses the measured values surrounding the prediction location.</description></item><item><title>basic sorting algorithms implemented in golang</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/basic-sorting-algorithms-implemented-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/basic-sorting-algorithms-implemented-in-golang/</guid><description>This post includes go-lang based implementation of some of the classic sorting algorithms.
This article primarily, has been written, as an academic exercise, to not forget the basic principles of sorting.
Bubble Sort wiki Bubble sort is perhaps the simplest of all sorting algorithms, the basic principle is to bubble up the largest (or the smallest) and then the second largest and then the third largest and so on. Each bubble takes the full sweep of the list, hence best-case, average-case as well as the worst-case performance are all O(n2)</description></item><item><title>reading and writing binary files in go lang</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/reading-and-writing-binary-files-in-go-lang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/reading-and-writing-binary-files-in-go-lang/</guid><description>Reading and writing binary files can often be a fast and very efficient alternatives to csv. They obviously have their challenges, however in this post I intent to present a very basic example of saving models (struct) into binary file and later reading it.
package main import ( &amp;ldquo;log&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;os&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;encoding/binary&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;bytes&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;fmt&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;math/rand&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; ) //this type represnts a record with three fields type payload struct { One float32 Two float64 Three uint32 } func main() { writeFile() readFile() } func readFile() { file, err := os.</description></item><item><title>Create linear color gradient in go</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/create-linear-color-gradient-in-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/create-linear-color-gradient-in-go/</guid><description>Go doesn't have any builtin gradient functions to paint/fill the background of a raster, however it has all the required primitives one needs to create a very basic linear gradient.
Here is a basic code which defines a 256 x 256 image, then calculates the value of each pixel in the raster based on a linear interpolation formula.
package main import ( &amp;ldquo;image&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;image/color&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;image/png&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;log&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;os&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;os/exec&amp;rdquo; ) var( colorB = [3]float64{248, 54, 0} colorA = [3]float64{254, 140, 0} ) var( width = 256 height = 256 max = float64(width) ) func linearGradient(x, y float64) (uint8, uint8, uint8) { d := x/max r := colorA[0] + d * (colorB[0] - colorA[0]) g := colorA[1] + d * (colorB[1] - colorA[1]) b := colorA[2] + d * (colorB[2] - colorA[2]) return uint8(r), uint8(g), uint8(b) } func main() { var w, h int = width, height dst := image.</description></item><item><title>merge sort in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/merge-sort-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/merge-sort-in-python/</guid><description>Many useful algorithms are recursive in structure: to solve a given problem, they call themselves recursively one or more times to deal with closely related subproblems. These algorithms typically follow a divide-and-conquer approach: they break the problem into several subproblems that are similar to the original problem but smaller in size, solve the subproblems recursively, and then combine these solutions to create a solution to the original problem. The divide-and-conquer paradigm involves three steps at each level of the recursion:</description></item><item><title>Using Geotiff as datasource via gdal</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/using-geotiff-as-datasource-via-gdal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/using-geotiff-as-datasource-via-gdal/</guid><description>Recently, I have been working on algorithms which needs elevation data as well as Land Cover data, with world coverage. Google has an excellent elevation API however free usage comes with a limit.
While searching, I came across a dataset in geotiff format for landcover as well as a processed version of world elevation. Elevation data comes in various resolution (250m,500m,1km), landcover is 500m .
So how do we read it ?</description></item><item><title>How to create fishnets or geospatial grids</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-create-fishnets-or-geospatial-grids/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-create-fishnets-or-geospatial-grids/</guid><description>There are many use cases in GIS world, where the information has to be aggregated, an easy way to achieve this is via gridding or binning, where the area of interest is divided into small sections called grids or bins.
These sections are mostly of rectangular form (which can be easily converted into geotiffs), but in some cases even circles or hexagons are also used.
You can read a good tutorial from mapbox using Qgis with a mmqgis plugin here.</description></item><item><title>How to transform projections between Spherical Mercator and EPSG 4326</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-transform-projections-between-spherical-mercator-and-epsg-4326/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-transform-projections-between-spherical-mercator-and-epsg-4326/</guid><description>Projections in GIS are commonly referred to by their “EPSG” codes, these are identifiers managed by the European Petroleum Survey Group.
One common identifier is “EPSG:4326”, which describes maps where latitude and longitude are treated as X/Y values.
Spherical Mercator has an official designation of EPSG:3857. However, before this was established, a large amount of software used the identifier EPSG:900913. This is an unofficial code, but is still the commonly usedin many GIS systems.</description></item><item><title>How to Query a Shape file for Point inside a polygon using ogr python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-query-a-shape-file-for-point-inside-a-polygon-using-ogr-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-query-a-shape-file-for-point-inside-a-polygon-using-ogr-python/</guid><description>Recently I was trying to build a quick geo lookup service in python, which could be used like an &amp;ldquo;info tool&amp;rdquo; in QGIS. This task is trivial in almost all geospatial databases, however I wasn't able to find much online around querying a shape file.
In this post I will demonstrate a simple python code to query a shape file which contains world countries. The file can be downloaded from here.</description></item><item><title>How to read a csv file in go</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-read-a-csv-file-in-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-read-a-csv-file-in-go/</guid><description>One of the most common task for a programmer is either to read or write a csv file
Read a csv file package main import ( &amp;ldquo;bufio&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;encoding/csv&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;os&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;fmt&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;io&amp;rdquo; ) func main() { // Load a csv file. f, _ := os.Open(&amp;quot;/path/to/my/csv/file.csv&amp;rdquo;) // Create a new reader. r := csv.NewReader(bufio.NewReader(f)) //define seperator r.Comma = &amp;lsquo;,&amp;rsquo; for { record, err := r.Read() // Stop at EOF. if err == io.</description></item><item><title>How to integrate Google container engine with Stackdriver with kubernaties</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-integrate-google-container-engine-with-stackdriver-with-kubernaties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-integrate-google-container-engine-with-stackdriver-with-kubernaties/</guid><description>Most folks have been using Grafana or something similar to monitor Kubernaties cluster.
If you are using Google cloud container engine , then the standard unified place to monitor all your application and services is Slackdriver.
According to googles documentation, when you create a new container cluster using GUI or gcloud, Slackdriver is automatically configured with a sink, however It did not work out of the box for me hence this post :)</description></item><item><title>Binary Search Tree in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/binary-search-tree-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/binary-search-tree-in-python/</guid><description>BST data structure supports many dynamic-set operations including
Search Minimum Maximum Predecessor Successor Insert Delete These basic operations allow us to treat this data structure both as a dictionary and as a priority queue. Basic operations on a binary tree takes time proportional to the height of the tree, O(lg n) [worst case] and even O(n) if the tree is a linear chain.
If you want to learn more about practical application of these trees check this post out.</description></item><item><title>Heap Sort in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/heap-sort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/heap-sort/</guid><description>The (binary) heap data structure is an array object that we can view as a nearly complete binary tree. Each node of the tree corresponds to an element of the array. The tree is completely filled on all levels except possibly the lowest, which is filled from the left up to a point. An array A that represents a heap is an object with two attributes: * length, which (as usual) gives the number of elements in the array.</description></item><item><title>Insertion sort in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/insertion-sort-in-python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/insertion-sort-in-python/</guid><description>Insertion sort, is an efficient algorithm for sorting a small number of elements.
Insertion sort works the way many people sort a hand of playing cards. We start with an empty left hand and the cards face down on the table. We then remove one card at a time from the table and insert it into the correct position in the left hand.
To find the correct position for a card, we compare it with each of the cards already in the hand, from right to left.</description></item><item><title>How to install Ubuntu bash on windows</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-ubuntu-bash-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-ubuntu-bash-on-windows/</guid><description>Microsoft announced at Build 2016 , about the new feature to run native Bash and GNU/Linux command-line tools
Gabriel Aul has just announced the release of the Windows 10 build #14316 to the Windows Insiders Fast-Ring
This build contains the first public release of Bash on Ubuntu on Windows and the underlying Windows Subsystem for Linux.
Turn on Developer Mode: Settings | Update &amp;amp; Security | For Developers | Check the Developer Mode radio button:</description></item><item><title>How to use Google Appengine Remote API for Java</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-use-google-appengine-remote-api-for-java/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-use-google-appengine-remote-api-for-java/</guid><description>Google App Engine Remote API enables programmers to access Google DataStore remotely from any python script or a Java Program.
Remote api essentially is a generic web service, which allows datastore to be accessed from outside the app engine's environment therefore using this mechanism, users can either bulk insert data or modify existing data from their servers.
With the help of remote api, data from one datastore can be copied to data on another app engine instance as well.</description></item><item><title>Read GAE Admin Backups fromLevelDB format and export GAE Entities using bulkloader</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/read-gae-admin-backups-fromleveldb-format-and-export-gae-entities-using-bulkloader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/read-gae-admin-backups-fromleveldb-format-and-export-gae-entities-using-bulkloader/</guid><description>Google datastore is pretty awesome when one needs a quick no-sql data storage. However recently I have experienced a problem in exporting my GAE Datastore as csv and in certain cases as a line delimited Json file. Its not very hard to do so and perhaps the easiest way to handle such thing is to write an export handler in you web app, however, there are alternative ways which I have highlighted below.</description></item><item><title>Serving raster layers on Google Cloud Platform</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/serving-raster-layers-on-google-cloud-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/serving-raster-layers-on-google-cloud-platform/</guid><description>In this blog post, I will write about using Google cloud storage as a Raster Tile Server for static imagery.
In the GIS domain, various techniques are used to add custom raster overlay on top of a base maps, or to even use custom imagery, as a base map itself.
This approach is also useful if you have a large quantity of satellite or aerial imagery, that you need to serve at scale onto a Google map or any other GIS tool.</description></item><item><title>Install all Go project dependencies in one command</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/install-all-go-project-dependencies-in-one-command/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/install-all-go-project-dependencies-in-one-command/</guid><description>So if you are looking to compile you go project on your server, you would probably need to worry about any third party dependencies.
Here is quick recursive way to do that
go get ./&amp;hellip;
Hope this helps</description></item><item><title>Bubble-sort in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/bubble-sort-in-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/bubble-sort-in-python/</guid><description>Bubble sort is a sorting algo that repeatedly steps through the list to be sorted, compares each pair of adjacent items and swaps them if they are in the wrong order.
It is a popular, but inefficient sorting algo, it has worst-case and average complexity both О(n2), where n is the number of items being sorted.
Here is an implementation in python
def bubbleSort(B): count = len(B) for i in xrange(count): for j in xrange(count-1,i,-1): #print &amp;ldquo;compairing %i with %i&amp;rdquo;%(B[j],B[j-1]) if B[j] &amp;lt; B[j - 1]: temp = B[j] B[j] = B[j - 1] B[j - 1] = temp #print &amp;ldquo;Swapping %i with %i&amp;rdquo;%(B[j],B[j-1]) #print &amp;ldquo;Transformed Array: &amp;quot; , B B = [6,5,3,1,8,7,2,4] print &amp;ldquo;Unsorted: &amp;ldquo;, B bubbleSort(B) print &amp;ldquo;Bubble Sorted: &amp;ldquo;, B Hope this helps</description></item><item><title>ultimate developer and power users tool list for mac and linux</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/ultimate-developer-and-power-users-tool-list-for-mac-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/ultimate-developer-and-power-users-tool-list-for-mac-and-linux/</guid><description>This is a collection of tools and utilities which I have found indispensable as an engineer. Each has a distinct purpose, and I probably touch each at least a few times a week. These tools save me time and I hope that you will find some of them useful as well.
Productivity s-tui s-tui is a terminal UI for monitoring your computer. s-tui allows to monitor CPU temperature, frequency, power and utilization in a graphical way from the terminal.</description></item><item><title>Creating Isochrones and Isodistances using Googles Direction Search API</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/creating-isochrones-and-isodistances-using-googles-direction-search-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/creating-isochrones-and-isodistances-using-googles-direction-search-api/</guid><description>Introduction Isochrones are curves of equal travel time from a certain point of origin, another way of saying this would be that an Isochrone is an isoline for travel time, if the weighting factor is changed form time to distance, then the resulting curve us called an Isodistance.
In this post I will present a rough way to create an Isochrone and an Isodistance using google's directions API.
Algorithm The actual algorithm to calculate Isocrone or Isodistance is perhpas a bit complicated than the simplistic approach being described here, if you are intrested in having a deeper look then I would recommend visiting this link by OpenStreetMap folks.</description></item><item><title>Tilestache on google maps</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/tilestache-on-google-maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/tilestache-on-google-maps/</guid><description>Introduction In this post I will demonstrate how to add custom TileStache map tiles on google maps, using google maps JavaScript API V3. TileStache has emerged as one of the easiest way to render your own map .There are many examples out there on creating basic tiles and then adding them on top of Leaftlet or Openlayers. In this post I will add them as an overlay on Google Maps.</description></item><item><title>Merge multiple Shapefiles using OGR2OGR in windows Linux or OSX</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/merge-multiple-shapefiles-using-ogr2ogr-in-windows-linux-or-osx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/merge-multiple-shapefiles-using-ogr2ogr-in-windows-linux-or-osx/</guid><description>Introduction This post is aimed at providing assistance to folks who are trying to merge many shapefiles into one single file in either windows or linux environment. Stuff like this may seem obvious to power users of GDAL/OGR, but not to those that are just new to using these great free tools.
Merging Shape (*.shp) Files on Windows Essentially, these commands will grab every shapefile in a directory, and merge them into a single file called “merged.</description></item><item><title>HTML Geolocation and Altitude</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/html-geolocation-and-altitude/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/html-geolocation-and-altitude/</guid><description>HTML5 Geolocation is a feature which allows the browser on a computer or a mobile phone, to acquire the position from the wifi,2g/3g/4g network or GPS.
The HTML Geolocation API is used to get the geographical position of a user. Since this can compromise user privacy, the position is not available unless the user approves it. The simplest way to use it through navigator.geolocation object if (navigator.geolocation) { navigator.geolocation.getCurrentPosition(showPosition); function showPosition(position) { alert(position.</description></item><item><title>Classes and Inheritance in EcmaScript 6 (ES6 Harmony)</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/classes-and-inheritance-in-ecmascript-6-es6-harmony/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/classes-and-inheritance-in-ecmascript-6-es6-harmony/</guid><description>So if you are a JavaScript geek and haven't yet heard,(if every one is listening to ECMA announcements, who's gonna drink beer :) ) ECMA 6 feature set has been drafted,its feature set is frozen, it is mostly being refined now. You can already program in it and compile it to current JavaScript . The JavaScript frameworks AngularJS and Ember.js will be based on it (with ways to opt out).</description></item><item><title>longest palindrome in a string</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/longest-palindrome-in-a-string/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/longest-palindrome-in-a-string/</guid><description>def isPailenDrome(s): if len(s)==1: return False L = len(s) for i in range(L): if s[i] != s[L-1-i]: return False return True def longestPalindrome(s): L = len(s) if len(s)&amp;lt;=1: return s if isPailenDrome(s): return s p = {} for u in range(L): for v in range(u+1,L+1): k = s[u:v] # print k,isPailenDrome(k) if isPailenDrome(k): p[len(k)] = k if len(p) &amp;gt; 0: return p[sorted(p,reverse = True)[0]] return s[0]</description></item><item><title>print two-dimensional array in spiral order</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/print-two-dimensional-array-in-spiral-order/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/print-two-dimensional-array-in-spiral-order/</guid><description>So I saw this problem in a book today about printing a 2d matrix in spiral order
Here are two solutions to it
Solution one. def printSpiralTL(m,x1,y1,x2,y2): for i in range(x1,x2): print m[y1][i] for j in range(y1+1,y2+1): print m[j][x2-1] if x2-x1 &amp;gt; 0: printSpiralBL(m, x1, y1 + 1, x2-1, y2) def printSpiralBL(m,x1,y1,x2,y2): for i in range(x2-1,x1-1,-1): print m[y2][i] for j in range(y2-1,y1-1,-1): print m[j][x1] if x2-x1 &amp;gt; 0: printSpiralTL(m, x1+1, y1, x2, y2-1) m = [ [1, 2, 3, 4], [5, 6, 7, 8], [9, 0, 1, 2], [3, 4, 5, 6], [7, 8, 9, 1] ] printSpiralTL(m,0,0,4,4)</description></item><item><title>merge two sorted arrays in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/merge-two-sorted-arrays-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/merge-two-sorted-arrays-in-python/</guid><description>Here is a quick code snippet to merge two sorted arrays in python
def merge(a,b): merged = [] l = 0 r = 0 for i in range(len(a)+len(b) ): lval = None rval = None if l &amp;lt; len(a): lval = a[l] if r &amp;lt; len(b): rval = b[r] if (lval &amp;lt; rval and rval and lval) or rval == None: merged.append(lval) l+=1 elif (lval &amp;gt;= rval and rval and lval)or lval == None: merged.</description></item><item><title>Update the locate DB on OS X</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/update-the-locate-db-on-os-x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/update-the-locate-db-on-os-x/</guid><description>Apparently out OS X does not have an updatedb command like linux has, so I was stumped on how to update the locate database.
I have quickly added this command here, incase I need to use it again.
sudo /usr/libexec/locate.updatedb</description></item><item><title>How to print the Fibonacci Sequence in Python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-print-the-fibonacci-sequence-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-print-the-fibonacci-sequence-in-python/</guid><description>The Fibonacci numbers are the sequence of numbers defined by the linear recurrence equation
![ F_n=F_(n-1)+F_(n-2) ](http://mathworld.wolfram.com/images/equations/FibonacciNumber/NumberedEquation1.gif) with ![F_1=F_2=1](http://mathworld.wolfram.com/images/equations/FibonacciNumber/Inline2.gif) and ![F_0=0](http://mathworld.wolfram.com/images/equations/FibonacciNumber/Inline3.gif) So in simple terms a method to compute fibonacci number for nth place looks like this
def fibonacci(n): if n == 0 or n ==1: return n else: return fibonacci(n-1)+fibonacci(n-2) here is quick test
for i in range(10): print i,&amp;rdquo; : &amp;ldquo;,fibonacci(i) #This will print 0 : 0 1 : 1 2 : 1 3 : 2 4 : 3 5 : 5 6 : 8 7 : 13 8 : 21 9 : 34 or an inline method like this print [fibonacci(i) for i in range(11)] will result</description></item><item><title>Using ElasticSearch for Spatial Search tutorial</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/using-elasticsearch-for-spatial-search-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/using-elasticsearch-for-spatial-search-tutorial/</guid><description>In this post I will demonstrate using ElasticSearch to spatially query records and filter them by attributes.
ElasticSearch is built on top of Lucence which in version 4.0 supports Spatial query features, for those interested here is an example and link to javadocs.
You will need to install ElasticSearch, read about installing it here, also install marvel plugin for configuration and testing.
For this demonstration I have used data from Geofabrik.</description></item><item><title>CCS3 only Loading Icon</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/ccs3-only-loading-icon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/ccs3-only-loading-icon/</guid><description>I generally have been using loading gifs in my work most of the time to inform the user that the resources are being fetched asynchronously from the server.
Ajaxload website is perhaps one of the most used site to download a suitable gif.
In this post I will demonstrate a css3 only way to create a nice loading simulation
Basic Code We will use nested divs to create the loading animation control and css looks like this body{ background-color: #fff; text-align: center; height: 100%; } html { height: 100%; overflow: hidden; } .</description></item><item><title>How to install and configure grunt on mac Osx</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-and-configure-grunt-on-mac-osx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-and-configure-grunt-on-mac-osx/</guid><description>This post is intended to assist folks who are trying to install and work with grunt on mac osx
Install Node.js and</description></item><item><title>Normalizing Ranges of Numbers</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/normalizing-ranges-of-numbers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/normalizing-ranges-of-numbers/</guid><description>Range Normalization is a normalization technique that allows you to map a number to a specific range.
Lets say that we have a data set where the values are in a range of 1 to 10, however we wish to normalise it to a range between 0 and 5
Mathematically speaking the equation comes down to
translated to Python
from __future__ import division class Normaliser: def __init__(self,dH,dL,nH,nL): self.dH = dH self.</description></item><item><title>Install tile-stache on OsX Mavericks</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/install-tile-stache-on-osx-mavericks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/install-tile-stache-on-osx-mavericks/</guid><description>This is quick tutorial about installing Tilestache library in OSX Mavericks.
Step 1 Make sure Developer tools are installed xcode-select &amp;ndash;install
Then add these flags to tell xcode to use python like rest of the world does
export CFLAGS=-Qunused-arguments
export CPPFLAGS=-Qunused-arguments
Finally type in sudo easy_install tilestache
Thats it all done, you might see some warnings but thats fine ignore them .
Read the introduction here to get started
Hope it helps.</description></item><item><title>how to make a web crawler in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-make-a-web-crawler-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-make-a-web-crawler-in-python/</guid><description>Here is a very simple web crawler in python
import sys, thread, Queue, re, urllib, urlparse, time, os, sys dupcheck = set() q = Queue.Queue(100) q.put(&amp;ldquo;http://www.varunpant.com&amp;quot;) def queueURLs(html, origLink): for url in re.findall(''']+href=&amp;quot;'[&amp;quot;']''', html, re.I): link = url.split(&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;, 1)[0] if url.startswith(&amp;ldquo;http&amp;rdquo;) else &amp;lsquo;{uri.scheme}://{uri.netloc}'.format(uri=urlparse.urlparse(origLink)) + url.split(&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;, 1)[0] if link in dupcheck: continue dupcheck.add(link) if len(dupcheck) &amp;gt; 99999: dupcheck.clear() q.put(link) def getHTML(link): try: html = urllib.urlopen(link).read() print link # open(str(time.time()) + &amp;ldquo;.html&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Ternary search tree</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/ternary-search-tree/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/ternary-search-tree/</guid><description>In computer science, a ternary search tree is a type of prefix tree where nodes are arranged as a binary search tree. Like other prefix trees, a ternary search tree can be used as an associative map structure with the ability for incremental string search. However, ternary search trees are more space efficient compared to standard prefix trees, at the cost of speed. Common applications for ternary search trees include spell-checking and auto-completion.</description></item><item><title>Gheat Java – Heat maps</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/gheat-java-heat-maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/gheat-java-heat-maps/</guid><description>A heat map is a graphical representation of data where the individual values contained in a matrix are represented as colors.
This article will attempt to explain the process or creating and using GHEAT-JAVA, which is a port of famous aspen based gheat and took great inspiration from Gheat.net
Writing a service which would serve heat map tiles is a bit tricky,there are three major components involved
The client part i.</description></item><item><title>Raphael-js-tutorial-part-II</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/raphael-js-tutorial-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/raphael-js-tutorial-part-ii/</guid><description>This is second part of the tutorial about getting started with Raphael.js. To see this first part go here.
Writing Text with Raphael Some code first ;) var canvas = Raphael(0, 0, 250, 250 ); var t = canvas.text(50, 50, &amp;ldquo;Some text Goes here&amp;rdquo;); var t2 = canvas.text(60,90,&amp;ldquo;First line \n Second Line \n Third line&amp;rdquo;); var t3 = canvas.text(214, 140, &amp;ldquo;1079&amp;rdquo;).attr({&amp;ldquo;text-anchor&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;middle&amp;rdquo;,&amp;lsquo;font-size&amp;rsquo;:16,&amp;ldquo;font-family&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;arial&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;fill&amp;rdquo;:&amp;quot;#fff&amp;rdquo;}); In the above examples canvas.text will create a simple text element at 50,50.</description></item><item><title>Turn Off Autocomplete for Input</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/turn-off-autocomplete-for-input/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/turn-off-autocomplete-for-input/</guid><description>The autocomplete attribute specifies whether or not an input field should have autocomplete enabled.
Autocomplete allows the browser to predict the value from locally saved history/cache. When a user starts to type in a field, the browser should display options to fill in the field, based on earlier typed values.
Note: The autocomplete attribute works with the following types: text, search, url, tel, email, password, datepickers, range, and color.
example usage:</description></item><item><title>Embedding Flash,Quicktime,Windows Media,Silverlight or HTML5 Video</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/embedding-flash-quicktime-windows-media-silverlight-or-html5-video/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/embedding-flash-quicktime-windows-media-silverlight-or-html5-video/</guid><description>Flash Object This is quick Snippet which demonstrate how to embed flash object in a web page.
### Quicktime
This is quick Snippet which demonstrate how to embed quicktime object in a web page
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;![endif]&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; ### Windows Media
This is quick Snippet which demonstrate how to embed Windows Media object in a web page.
### Silver Light
This is quick Snippet which demonstrate how to embed Silverlight object in a web page.</description></item><item><title>Mod Proxy equivalent in IIS using ARR and URL Rewrite Module</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/mod-proxy-equivalent-in-iis-using-arr-and-url-rewrite-module/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/mod-proxy-equivalent-in-iis-using-arr-and-url-rewrite-module/</guid><description>IIS7 is quite modular, it is shipped with lots of goodies as separate modules and together it is now one of the most powerful and flexible web server.
In this post I intent to cover how we can easily configure ARR and URL Rewrite Module to get a similar functionality as of Mod Proxy in Apache.
Here I will demonstrate configuration of a reverse proxy which according to the definition is</description></item><item><title>Signing android release apk from the command line (via ant)</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/signing-android-release-apk-from-the-command-line-via-ant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/signing-android-release-apk-from-the-command-line-via-ant/</guid><description>This post is probably out too late ,as almost all IDE's these days (which support android development) ,probably have an Integrated release signing or debug signing utility/wizard built in, but if somebody is using an old IDE or perhaps want to integrate release in a CI(continues integration) environment , this tutorial might come in handy.
Basically one has to sign an apk either with a debug key (which is generally present in your .</description></item><item><title>Importing CSV File Into SQL SERVER Database using BULK INSERT</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/importing-csv-file-into-sql-server-database-using-bulk-insert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/importing-csv-file-into-sql-server-database-using-bulk-insert/</guid><description>Importing data into a database from a delimited file is perhaps one of the most common tasks that one might have to perform. SQL server gives us an import utility which supports various data sources and has an intutive interface as well,however there is another way which can be utilized to quickly get the job done, its called BULK INSERT
BULK INSERT is a SQL command which can be typed in management console,takes various parameters to control the import and is very simple to use.</description></item><item><title>Importing Exporting CSV Files in PostgreSQL Databases via COPY</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/importing-exporting-csv-files-in-postgresql-databases-via-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/importing-exporting-csv-files-in-postgresql-databases-via-copy/</guid><description>This is going to be a short article which will illustrate importing and exporting a table from or to a csv file using PostgreSQL COPY command.
Importing a table from CSV Assuming you already have a table in place with the right columns, the command is as follows
COPY FROM &amp;lsquo;/path/to/csv/SourceCSVFile.csv&amp;rsquo; DELIMITERS &amp;lsquo;,&amp;rsquo; CSV;
Exporting a CSV from a table. COPY TO &amp;lsquo;/path/to/csv/TargetCSVFile&amp;rsquo; DELIMITERS &amp;lsquo;,&amp;rsquo; CSV;
Its important to mention here that generally if your data is in unicode or need strict Encoding, then Always set client_encoding before running any of the above mentioned commands.</description></item><item><title>Raphael JS Tutorial - Part I</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/raphael-js-tutorial-part-i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/raphael-js-tutorial-part-i/</guid><description>Raphael.JS is a SVG/VML library which helps you to create quick vector shapes and images. Its very small and compact (only 86kb),easy to use,well documented and works in all browsers and yes even IE. Here is a list of all major browsers this library works on: Chrome 5.0+ Firefox 3.0+, Safari 3.0+, Opera 9.5+ and Internet Explorer 6.0+
,finally its distributed under MIT license. In this tutorial ,I intend to introduce basics of this library and help you get started.</description></item><item><title>How to configure Apache mod_wsgi</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-configure-apache-mod_wsgi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-configure-apache-mod_wsgi/</guid><description>I am a big fan and user of python. one of the most popular ways to create quick web app in python is via using mod wsgi.
The aim of mod_wsgi is to implement a simple to use Apache module which can host any Python application which supports the Python WSGI interface.
The module would be suitable for use in hosting high performance production web sites, as well as your average self managed personal sites running on web hosting services.</description></item><item><title>Serve the contents of any directory with Python's SimpleHTTPServer</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/serve-the-contents-of-any-directory-with-python-s-simplehttpserver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/serve-the-contents-of-any-directory-with-python-s-simplehttpserver/</guid><description>Generally, when I am in a middle of prototyping a concept or in a need of quickly executing Ajax requests or using browser features which would need the page to be hosted on a web server, I use Python's SimpleHTTPServer module.
Python's SimpleHTTPServer is a great way of serve the contents of the current directory,all one needs to do is change directory and execute a command which will expose all contents as if they were hosted in a web page.</description></item><item><title>Avoid console errors in browsers that lack a console</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/avoid-console-errors-in-browsers-that-lack-a-console/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/avoid-console-errors-in-browsers-that-lack-a-console/</guid><description>I love JavaScript and code a lot in it .Since I code, I also encounter problems and bugs from time to time and therefore need a Debugger and a debug mechanism to view whats going on.
In good old days when I learned this language, I used JavaScript's inbuilt alert mechanism to view the value of a variable or a property of an object. This was a terrible mechanism, calling alert was blocking, one had to press OK to continue and if you had to take a look inside an array then well it was emotionally an overwhelming task is all I would say here.</description></item><item><title>sqlite3 Bulk Import CSV from command line</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/sqlite3-bulk-import-csv-from-command-line/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/sqlite3-bulk-import-csv-from-command-line/</guid><description>I absolutely love SQLite, be it windows, linux or mac, this light weight database never stops to amaze me.
Few days ago I wanted to import a chunk of CSV data, which was 4 GB in size into a table in SQLite.
I generally use Firefox &amp;lsquo;s sqlite-manager plug-in for usual tasks with SQLite database ,hence decided to use the import interface .
I have had a very good experience with this GUI tool and it has rarely failed me, but this time I was disappointed.</description></item><item><title>Install Apache Cassandra</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/install-apache-cassandra/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/install-apache-cassandra/</guid><description>Cassandra is an Open Source Distributed Data Persistence system which is designed for storing and managing large amounts of data across servers.
To quote elevator pitch by Eben Hewitt</description></item><item><title>Position div in the center of the page using css</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/position-div-in-the-center-of-the-page-using-css/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/position-div-in-the-center-of-the-page-using-css/</guid><description>When I first started web programming, creating a center aligned div was one of the most common task that I saw myself doing.
since div is a block element, i.e. it takes up the full width available, and has a line break before and after it, it can easily be centered using relative styling
.center { margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:70%; background-color:#b0e0e6; } However lately I have preferred using absolute positioning technique over relative, this works for all browsers and is best for login screens or alert messages over a translucent shim.</description></item><item><title>A guide to hosting in Red Hats OpenShift PaaS</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/a-guide-to-hosting-in-red-hats-openshift-paas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/a-guide-to-hosting-in-red-hats-openshift-paas/</guid><description>In this post,I am going to write about OpenShift, which is Red hat's free, auto-scaling Platform as a Service (PaaS) for applications.
OpenShift to me is very similar to Google's app engine in some ways,but openshift's offerings are quite diverse, for instance support for ruby, php, Perl, node.js, etc..
Openshift is not like a traditional VPS hosting , although once registered with them, user does get a shell access,but its quite limited , instead OpenShift has a concept of gears and cartridges.</description></item><item><title>Basic authentication in web.py via attribute</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/basic-authentication-in-web-py-via-attribute/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/basic-authentication-in-web-py-via-attribute/</guid><description>Here I demonstrate the process of Basic Authentication in web.py python web framework.
There is a proof of concept article provided in the main site,however I just thought doing the same via an attribute might be a cleaner solution.
HTTP Basic authentication implementation is one of the easiest ways to secure web pages because it doesn't require cookies, session handling, or the development of login pages. Rather, HTTP Basic authentication uses static headers which means that no handshakes have to be done in anticipation,however the n the credentials are passed as plain-text and could be intercepted.</description></item><item><title>Cross browser drop shadow with CSS3</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/cross-browser-drop-shadow-with-css3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/cross-browser-drop-shadow-with-css3/</guid><description>When css3 arrived, one of the goodies that I found was, the inclusion of Drop Shadow effect, namely **Box Shadow **and Text Shadow.
Here I present a cross browser utility css class which can be used for a drop shadow effect, without any image.
.shadow { /* For IE 8 / -ms-filter: &amp;ldquo;progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.Shadow(Strength=4, Direction=135, Color=&amp;rsquo;#000000&amp;rsquo;)&amp;quot;; / For IE 5.5 - 7 / filter: progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.Shadow(Strength=4, Direction=135, Color=&amp;rsquo;#000000&amp;rsquo;); -moz-box-shadow: 3px 3px 4px #000; -webkit-box-shadow: 3px 3px 4px #000; box-shadow: 3px 3px 4px #000; } For cross browser text shadow effect ,I found a nice article here.</description></item><item><title>Cross browser CSS3 border-radius (rounded corners)</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/cross-browser-css3-border-radius-rounded-corners/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/cross-browser-css3-border-radius-rounded-corners/</guid><description>When I started programming and had to begin designing my first user interface in HTML, I was always puzzled as to why are all visual elements in HTML rectangular. I soon learned that in those days if one would want a circle to be drawn on a page, then the only way possible was using an image, the same was true for drawing elements with rounded corners.
Thankfully HTML5/CSS3 guys were listening and the latest css3 standard supports defining the corner radius of a circle, this can be used to make an element look like a circle too if you want.</description></item><item><title>Cross Browser Opacity or Transparency</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/cross-browser-opacity-or-transparency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/cross-browser-opacity-or-transparency/</guid><description>Css has a very useful property called Opacity, which basically is a measure of transparency of an element.
All modern browsers Yes yes even IE has support for it.
In most browsers the value is between 0 minimum [transparent] i.e not visible to 1 maximum [opaque] i.e. completely visible
In IE the value is between 0 and 100 ,don't ask why they just like to make us unhappy.
Here I present a helper css class which will work in all browsers.</description></item><item><title>Installing Redis on Ubuntu</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/installing-redis-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/installing-redis-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>Redis is an open source, advanced key-value store. Installing it on Linux debian platforms is pretty easy.
There are two ways of getting this done, one is perhaps an easy and less verbose method and it involves using an alternative repository Dotdeb.
A while ago I had posted a tutorial about installing redis from the googlecode repo, but things have changed since then and here I post a fairly latest way of installing it.</description></item><item><title>gzip compression in apache using mod_deflate</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/gzip-compression-in-apache-using-mod_deflate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/gzip-compression-in-apache-using-mod_deflate/</guid><description>HTTP Compression is a very simple and effective way to save bandwidth and improve web applications performance over network.
Output compression is basically a process of compressing web servers response by using a loss-less compression algorithm called gzip.
This technique is fairly modern and almost all modern browsers honor it, however if a page is requested from a browser which does not send a header Accept-Encoding: gzip,deflate then the response comes back uncompressed.</description></item><item><title>Start Stop Restart Apache 2 Web Server</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/start-stop-restart-apache-2-web-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/start-stop-restart-apache-2-web-server/</guid><description>I have been using Linux environment a lot lately, particularly for hosting my web experiments and other application. One of the biggest and most searched question for newbies have been
How do I restart Apache 2 Web Server under Debian / Ubuntu Linux or UNIX operating systems?
In this post I simply attempt to lay this down for my and their benifit.
Start Apache2 # sudo /etc/init.d/apache2 start</description></item><item><title>Factorial in python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/factorial-in-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/factorial-in-python/</guid><description>Mathematically, the formula for the factorial is as follows. If n is an integer greater than or equal to 1, then n ! = n ( n - 1)( n - 2)( n - 3) &amp;hellip; (3)(2)(1) If p = 0, then p ! = 1 by convention.
def factorial(n): if n == 0: return 1 else: return n * factorial(n-1) Hope this helps</description></item><item><title>Auto Complete with Redis (Python)</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/auto-complete-with-redis-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/auto-complete-with-redis-python/</guid><description>This is a quick port of auto complete implementation in ruby using Redis by antirez.
I like python and had little time to burn today, so here goes:
The file used for input is female-names.txt
Hope it helps :)</description></item><item><title>How To Install and use Python Web.py framework on Windows</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-and-use-python-webpy-framework-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-install-and-use-python-webpy-framework-on-windows/</guid><description>Web.py has been one of my favorite web frameworks as its pretty easy to get cracking on it.
It's super quick to install and one can come up with a prototype and rapid web services in matter of minutes.
Install on windows If you haven't configured easy_install on windows, then read this article.
Once easy_install has been configured believe it or not, all you have to do is open a command prompt and type</description></item><item><title>How to setup easy_install on Windows</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-setup-easy_install-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-setup-easy_install-on-windows/</guid><description>If one has been using python, then installing various libraries and modules is basically a breeze using easy_install utility, however for folks using windows, easy_install utility has to be setup properly before using it.
First lets make sure that python is properly installed and PYTHON_HOME environment variable is configured:
Install Python on Windows If not already installed download python installer from here.
After it's done downloading, double click to run the installer, and select default options (unless you have other custom needs of course ).</description></item><item><title>Find Longitude and Latitude in Google Maps</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/find-longitude-and-latitude-in-google-maps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/find-longitude-and-latitude-in-google-maps/</guid><description>This post is basically a way of quick appreciation to the Google maps Team, they are obviously a bunch of caring, loving people ,who make useful (although surreptitious) tools for the betterment of Geek Kind.
So as most of you may have accidently clicked a mysterious looking link at the bottom of your Google maps page ( on the left hand panel)
This awesome looking link opens up a popup which lets you choose wonderful goodies which makes your Google maps page more useful than it already is:</description></item><item><title>How to set up Redis in Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-set-up-redis-in-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/how-to-set-up-redis-in-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>Redis is an open source, advanced key-value store, and is quickly picking up momentum in real-time software development , it is now a well known and trusted product and can be used in various problem scenarios as a No SQL implementation.
Redis is often referred to as a data structure server since keys can contain strings, hashes, lists, sets and sorted sets.
Here is quick guide to Install Redis in Ubuntu 10.</description></item><item><title>Installing Ubuntu Linux in VMware and VMwareTools</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/installing-ubuntu-linux-in-vmware-and-vmwaretools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/installing-ubuntu-linux-in-vmware-and-vmwaretools/</guid><description>I have been using Ubuntu for last two years as a deployment environment for my pet projects, however recently, after having installed “Natty Narwhal” on one of my old ‘HP’ laptop I moved into using Ubuntu as a full time development environment.
There are times when I need more than one deployment units and since I use Linodeas my primary deployment VPS host, I sometime need to test the perf of my software locally thus there came a need of replicating an exact or close to exact “Deployment Environment”</description></item><item><title>LIMBO Game Review</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/limbo-game-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/limbo-game-review/</guid><description>LIMBO is a horrifically beautiful, monochrome or rather a gray-scale purgatory painted perhaps while watching Tim burton movie on the side. It was published initially in Jul 2010 by Microsoft Game Studios(XBLA) and Playdead(PSN, Windows), and then later released for Windows platform by Steam.
The primary character of the game is a boy, who wakes up right at the beginning of the game i.e while you are trying to figure out WTF is happening or wonder if you graphics driver (windows platform) screwed up or something, but there as you are fiddling with the movement buttons in keyboard you will see pair of bright white eyes flickering, and that’s when you start falling in love with the game and the care of detail added in a game which is totally unlike other in its league.</description></item><item><title>VPS Hosting Past and Present</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/vps-hosting-past-and-present/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/vps-hosting-past-and-present/</guid><description>I had been hosting this blog in the past for an extremely competitive (read cheap) price here at Arvixe . I was using ASP.net based blogging software called BlogEngine. over and all I will describe my experience as pleasant. Arvixe is a great Hosting Provider, has good up time and has plans which are easy on the pocket, and does almost all the common stuff like emails and cpanel ,blah blah that other hosting provider do, but kinda does it on a low price.</description></item><item><title>Web Sockets in HTML 5</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/web-sockets-in-html-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/web-sockets-in-html-5/</guid><description>HTML5 WebSockets, defines a full-duplex communication channel that operates through a single socket over the web. WebSocket is not just another incremental enhancement to conventional HTTP communications, it represents a large advance, especially for real-time, event driven web applications.
Normally when a browser visits a web page, an HTTP request is sent to the web server that hosts that page. The web server acknowledges this request and sends back the response.</description></item><item><title>Water Simulation</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/water-simulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/water-simulation/</guid><description>Its been a while since my last post, had been busy with office work…sigh!!!
Anyways, I was poking around web to come up with interesting water simulation techniques, as you could see in many games these days, so I did find a reference to an old C-based technique, after little refinement, what I have is a water simulation which uses a very old algorithm based on two heightmaps.
As always it’s a grid based animation which divides the screen into a mesh(more slices better this simulation looks), I use a jagged array in c# to do this (load it with a texture of 640 X 480 dimension ), to animate I use another array of same dimensions, now to make every thing move I kinda do something like this</description></item><item><title>Liquid Particles</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/liquid-particles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/liquid-particles/</guid><description>After ages of constantly being one of the most used browser as well as a serious pain in Butt!!! IE is finally about to mature into something good and perhaps a useful software , with its support to most of the standards being used today , IE will join back the league of web 3.0 browsers, hopefully very soon
So I was going through various experiments done with Canvas and came across a great example on Liquid Particle physics simulation, which amazingly is written in JavaScript and Canvas element, I was so mesmerized by the application that I had to port it to SilverLight, using WritableBitmap.</description></item><item><title>Image Carousel</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/image-carousel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/image-carousel/</guid><description>Here is another of many JavaScript based Image Carousel, I had seen many similar to these made in SilverLight and Flash, I came across a wonderful carousel made in SilverLight sometimes back which was very fluid in behavior and could easily be customized and configured to take various shape and form.
I have managed to port it to JavaScript, it works best on chrome or FF, hope this would be fun to play with.</description></item><item><title>I-Phone Scroll</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/i-phone-scroll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/i-phone-scroll/</guid><description>One of the amazing features of i-phone user interface is smooth panning/scrolling animation.
I-phone “List Scrolling” perhaps gives a very funky and usable List –View to its users and allows them to scroll up and down the interface without any need of a scroll bar.
This interface is sensitive to the push speed and also shows traces of resilience.
I have been experimenting with various techniques to bring out similar effect using JavaScript and HTML, I am not quite sure if this would be useful in its present form but with some modifications may be this sample could prove its worthiness somewhere.</description></item><item><title>Data URI and IE</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/data-uri-and-ie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/data-uri-and-ie/</guid><description>Few days ago I was experimenting with a nifty technique of embedding images in web pages by base64 encoding them first and then using a standard known as Data URI Scheme, which basically defines a method of assigning a ‘src’ of an image tag as a base64 serialized string, like this:
background - image: url(&amp;ldquo;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABkAAAAUBAMAAACKWYuOAAAAMFBMVEX///92dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnZ2dnYvD4PNAAAAD3RSTlMAACTkfhvbh3iEewTtxBIFliR3AAAAUklEQVQY02NgIBMwijgKCgrAef5fkHnz/y9E4kn+/4XEE6z/34jEE///A4knev7zAwQv7L8RQk40/7MiggeUQpjJff+zIpINykbIbhFSROIRDQAWUhW2oXLWAQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&amp;rdquo;); Although this technique could save some server round trips, however Microsoft ver. (IE &amp;lt; 8). does not support this scheme even though its a standard, which then makes this technique unfavorable to use as its not cross browser.</description></item><item><title>Notepad++ with Python</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/notepad-with-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/notepad-with-python/</guid><description>After reading an excellent article by Kazi Manzur Rashidon setting up a development environment for Iron Ruby using Notepad++, I was immediately struck with an idea of using the same excellent tool with Python 2.6.
Now don’t get me wrong here, theoretically there is nothing wrong with IDLE, but having a light weight IDE for those who don’t want to use Pydevplugin for Aptanaor Eclipse, I think Notepad++ is indeed a nice little dev tool.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.github.io/weblog/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>After long period of wait, here it is my very first and personal Blogging Space.
I have been hoping to go online for about an year now, but then there always were events happening around to prevent this immense desire of mine.
I intend to blog about .net in general , JavaScript, Silverlight, Animation and maybe some other cool stuff .
Hope to update this space again.
Cheers!!!
&amp;ndash; Varun</description></item></channel></rss>