<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>redis on Varun Pant</title><link>https://varunpant.com/tags/redis/</link><description>Recent content in redis on Varun Pant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunpant.com/tags/redis/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Redis on Ubuntu</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-redis-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-redis-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>Redis is an open source, advanced key-value store. Installing it on Linux debian platforms is pretty easy.
There are two ways of getting this done, one is perhaps an easy and less verbose method and it involves using an alternative repository Dotdeb.
A while ago I had posted a tutorial about installing redis from the googlecode repo, but things have changed since then and here I post a fairly latest way of installing it.</description></item><item><title>Auto Complete with Redis (Python)</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/auto-complete-with-redis-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/auto-complete-with-redis-python/</guid><description>This is a quick port of auto complete implementation in ruby using Redis by antirez.
I like python and had little time to burn today, so here goes:
The file used for input is female-names.txt
Hope it helps :)</description></item><item><title>How to set up Redis in Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-set-up-redis-in-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-set-up-redis-in-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>Redis is an open source, advanced key-value store, and is quickly picking up momentum in real-time software development , it is now a well known and trusted product and can be used in various problem scenarios as a No SQL implementation.
Redis is often referred to as a data structure server since keys can contain strings, hashes, lists, sets and sorted sets.
Here is quick guide to Install Redis in Ubuntu 10.</description></item></channel></rss>