<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ubuntu on Varun Pant</title><link>https://varunpant.com/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in ubuntu on Varun Pant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunpant.com/tags/ubuntu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A guide to hosting in Red Hats OpenShift PaaS</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/a-guide-to-hosting-in-red-hats-openshift-paas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/a-guide-to-hosting-in-red-hats-openshift-paas/</guid><description>In this post,I am going to write about OpenShift, which is Red hat&amp;rsquo;s free, auto-scaling Platform as a Service (PaaS) for applications.
OpenShift to me is very similar to Google&amp;rsquo;s app engine in some ways,but openshift&amp;rsquo;s offerings are quite diverse, for instance support for ruby, php, Perl, node.js, etc..
Openshift is not like a traditional VPS hosting , although once registered with them, user does get a shell access,but its quite limited , instead OpenShift has a concept of gears and cartridges.</description></item><item><title>Installing Redis on Ubuntu</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-redis-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-redis-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>Redis is an open source, advanced key-value store. Installing it on Linux debian platforms is pretty easy.
There are two ways of getting this done, one is perhaps an easy and less verbose method and it involves using an alternative repository Dotdeb.
A while ago I had posted a tutorial about installing redis from the googlecode repo, but things have changed since then and here I post a fairly latest way of installing it.</description></item><item><title>Installing Ubuntu Linux in VMware and VMwareTools</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-ubuntu-linux-in-vmware-and-vmwaretools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-ubuntu-linux-in-vmware-and-vmwaretools/</guid><description>I have been using Ubuntu for last two years as a deployment environment for my pet projects, however recently, after having installed “Natty Narwhal” on one of my old ‘HP’ laptop I moved into using Ubuntu as a full time development environment.
There are times when I need more than one deployment units and since I use Linodeas my primary deployment VPS host, I sometime need to test the perf of my software locally thus there came a need of replicating an exact or close to exact “Deployment Environment”</description></item></channel></rss>