<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>general on Varun Pant</title><link>https://varunpant.com/tags/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on Varun Pant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunpant.com/tags/general/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>how to play apple music on alexa in uk</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-play-apple-music-on-alexa-in-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-play-apple-music-on-alexa-in-uk/</guid><description>You can now use Alexa to play Apple Music on Amazon Echo speakers.
It's just available for Echo devices and now customers in UK can also connect their apple music account with Alexa.
Open the Alexa app then sign into your Amazon account and make sure that your Echo device is connected.
Open Menu (top left icon), then select settings.
Select Music.
Select &amp;ldquo;Link New Service&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Normalizing Ranges of Numbers</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/normalizing-ranges-of-numbers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/normalizing-ranges-of-numbers/</guid><description>Range Normalization is a normalization technique that allows you to map a number to a specific range.
Lets say that we have a data set where the values are in a range of 1 to 10, however we wish to normalise it to a range between 0 and 5
Mathematically speaking the equation comes down to
translated to Python
class Normaliser: def \_\_init\_\_(self,dH,dL,nH,nL): self.dH = dH self.dL = dL self.</description></item><item><title>Gheat Java – Heat maps</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/gheat-java-heat-maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/gheat-java-heat-maps/</guid><description>A heat map is a graphical representation of data where the individual values contained in a matrix are represented as colors.
This article will attempt to explain the process or creating and using GHEAT-JAVA, which is a port of famous aspen based gheat and took great inspiration from Gheat.net
Writing a service which would serve heat map tiles is a bit tricky,there are three major components involved
The client part i.</description></item><item><title>Importing CSV File Into SQL SERVER Database using BULK INSERT</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/importing-csv-file-into-sql-server-database-using-bulk-insert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/importing-csv-file-into-sql-server-database-using-bulk-insert/</guid><description>Importing data into a database from a delimited file is perhaps one of the most common tasks that one might have to perform. SQL server gives us an import utility which supports various data sources and has an intutive interface as well,however there is another way which can be utilized to quickly get the job done, its called BULK INSERT
BULK INSERT is a SQL command which can be typed in management console,takes various parameters to control the import and is very simple to use.</description></item><item><title>How to configure Apache mod_wsgi</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-configure-apache-mod_wsgi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-configure-apache-mod_wsgi/</guid><description>I am a big fan and user of python. one of the most popular ways to create quick web app in python is via using mod wsgi.
The aim of mod_wsgi is to implement a simple to use Apache module which can host any Python application which supports the Python WSGI interface.
The module would be suitable for use in hosting high performance production web sites, as well as your average self managed personal sites running on web hosting services.</description></item><item><title>sqlite3 Bulk Import CSV from command line</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/sqlite3-bulk-import-csv-from-command-line/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/sqlite3-bulk-import-csv-from-command-line/</guid><description>I absolutely love SQLite, be it windows, linux or mac, this light weight database never stops to amaze me.
Few days ago I wanted to import a chunk of CSV data, which was 4 GB in size into a table in SQLite.
I generally use Firefox &amp;lsquo;s sqlite-manager plug-in for usual tasks with SQLite database ,hence decided to use the import interface .
I have had a very good experience with this GUI tool and it has rarely failed me, but this time I was disappointed.</description></item><item><title>A guide to hosting in Red Hats OpenShift PaaS</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/a-guide-to-hosting-in-red-hats-openshift-paas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/a-guide-to-hosting-in-red-hats-openshift-paas/</guid><description>In this post,I am going to write about OpenShift, which is Red hat's free, auto-scaling Platform as a Service (PaaS) for applications.
OpenShift to me is very similar to Google's app engine in some ways,but openshift's offerings are quite diverse, for instance support for ruby, php, Perl, node.js, etc..
Openshift is not like a traditional VPS hosting , although once registered with them, user does get a shell access,but its quite limited , instead OpenShift has a concept of gears and cartridges.</description></item><item><title>Auto Complete with Redis (Python)</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/auto-complete-with-redis-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/auto-complete-with-redis-python/</guid><description>This is a quick port of auto complete implementation in ruby using Redis by antirez.
I like python and had little time to burn today, so here goes:
The file used for input is female-names.txt
Hope it helps :)</description></item><item><title>How to setup easy_install on Windows</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-setup-easy_install-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/how-to-setup-easy_install-on-windows/</guid><description>If one has been using python, then installing various libraries and modules is basically a breeze using easy_install utility, however for folks using windows, easy_install utility has to be setup properly before using it.
First lets make sure that python is properly installed and PYTHON_HOME environment variable is configured:
Install Python on Windows If not already installed download python installer from here.
After it's done downloading, double click to run the installer, and select default options (unless you have other custom needs of course ).</description></item><item><title>Find Longitude and Latitude in Google Maps</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/find-longitude-and-latitude-in-google-maps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/find-longitude-and-latitude-in-google-maps/</guid><description>This post is basically a way of quick appreciation to the Google maps Team, they are obviously a bunch of caring, loving people ,who make useful (although surreptitious) tools for the betterment of Geek Kind.
So as most of you may have accidently clicked a mysterious looking link at the bottom of your Google maps page ( on the left hand panel)
This awesome looking link opens up a popup which lets you choose wonderful goodies which makes your Google maps page more useful than it already is:</description></item><item><title>Installing Ubuntu Linux in VMware and VMwareTools</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-ubuntu-linux-in-vmware-and-vmwaretools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/installing-ubuntu-linux-in-vmware-and-vmwaretools/</guid><description>I have been using Ubuntu for last two years as a deployment environment for my pet projects, however recently, after having installed “Natty Narwhal” on one of my old ‘HP’ laptop I moved into using Ubuntu as a full time development environment.
There are times when I need more than one deployment units and since I use Linodeas my primary deployment VPS host, I sometime need to test the perf of my software locally thus there came a need of replicating an exact or close to exact “Deployment Environment”</description></item><item><title>VPS Hosting Past and Present</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/vps-hosting-past-and-present/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/vps-hosting-past-and-present/</guid><description>I had been hosting this blog in the past for an extremely competitive (read cheap) price here at Arvixe . I was using ASP.net based blogging software called BlogEngine. over and all I will describe my experience as pleasant. Arvixe is a great Hosting Provider, has good up time and has plans which are easy on the pocket, and does almost all the common stuff like emails and cpanel ,blah blah that other hosting provider do, but kinda does it on a low price.</description></item><item><title>Notepad++ with Python</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/notepad-with-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/notepad-with-python/</guid><description>After reading an excellent article by Kazi Manzur Rashidon setting up a development environment for Iron Ruby using Notepad++, I was immediately struck with an idea of using the same excellent tool with Python 2.6.
Now don’t get me wrong here, theoretically there is nothing wrong with IDLE, but having a light weight IDE for those who don’t want to use Pydevplugin for Aptanaor Eclipse, I think Notepad++ is indeed a nice little dev tool.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://varunpant.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://varunpant.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>After long period of wait, here it is my very first and personal Blogging Space.
I have been hoping to go online for about an year now, but then there always were events happening around to prevent this immense desire of mine.
I intend to blog about .net in general , JavaScript, Silverlight, Animation and maybe some other cool stuff .
Hope to update this space again.
Cheers!!!
&amp;ndash; Varun</description></item></channel></rss>